<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>North Texas Aikido</title><link>https://northtexasaikido.com/</link><description>Recent content on North Texas Aikido</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://northtexasaikido.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gallery</title><link>https://northtexasaikido.com/gallery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 17:07:14 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://northtexasaikido.com/gallery/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About Iwama-Style Aikido</title><link>https://northtexasaikido.com/about/aikido/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://northtexasaikido.com/about/aikido/</guid><description>&lt;p>Aikido is written in Japanese using three characters. They are translated as “Ai” - Harmony, “Ki” - Spirit, and “Do” - the Way; or in one translation, &amp;ldquo;The way of spiritual harmony.&amp;rdquo; It is a comparatively modern and extremely sophisticated martial art. Being purely self-defensive, it stresses the avoidance of conflict as an integral part of its philosophical and technical tenets.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contact the Dojo</title><link>https://northtexasaikido.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://northtexasaikido.com/contact/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="contact-us">Contact Us&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>You may contact the dojo directly by phone during daylight hours by phone:&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 class="text-center mt-0 mb-3" id="hahahugoshortcode12s0hbhb">


 
 




&lt;a href="#" data-secret="dGVsOjk3MjM5MDk2MDA=" data-secrettext="OTcyLjM5MC45NjAw">&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>or you may fill out the form below to send a message or question to the dojo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We will contact you within two business days by phone or email.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dojo Etiquette</title><link>https://northtexasaikido.com/classes/etiquette/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://northtexasaikido.com/classes/etiquette/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="etiquette">Etiquette&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Courtesy in the dojo is more than just a tradition, it is an integral part of Aikido training. By creating a harmonious atmosphere, it aids in learning; and by practicing kindness towards others you work toward self-improvement. A dojo is a special place where people come together for mutual benefit. Here are a few simple things that are considered common courtesy in almost any dojo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;div class="boxed roundoff shadow">
 &lt;ul>
&lt;li>Bow to the Shomen whenever you enter or leave the dojo or step on or off the mat. This shows your respect for the art.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you arrive late, dress out and wait quietly at the edge of the mat for the instructor to notice you. He or she will call you onto the mat when it will be least disruptive to the class. Then do a formal bow to the Shomen.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The instructor is always addressed as Sensei. Bow to the Sensei before and after practice, and whenever you receive personal instruction.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sit quietly in seiza and maintain a straight posture when the sensei is demonstrating to the class.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Show respect to your partners by requesting that they practice with you and by thanking them afterward.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remember at all times that you are practicing for mutual improvement, and regardless of any rank differences, there is much you can learn from each other.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Shoes and jewelry should never be worn on the mat. Nails should be kept short; and feet, clothing, and language should be kept clean&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Personal hygiene is a must. Colognes and perfumes should not be worn; and remember that make-up rubs off on other people&amp;rsquo;s uniforms.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>There are many facets of dojo etiquette. The best way to learn is through observation, remembering that new students will soon be watching you in hopes of gaining information.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>

&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="container">
 &lt;div class="divider">
 &lt;img src="./images/MON.svg">
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dues</title><link>https://northtexasaikido.com/classes/dues/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://northtexasaikido.com/classes/dues/</guid><description>&lt;h1>
Monthly Dues
 &lt;span class="subheader text-small">November 25, 2024&lt;/span>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The traditional view is that one cannot buy this type of instruction; it must be given freely and the burden of learning rests solely on the student. The dues and fees you pay are merely a way of insuring that the dojo will be sustained and the at the training and instruction can continue to progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our payment policy is simple. Dues should be paid before the first of the month. We request that you be as prompt as possible. Like everyone else, we have financial obligations and like to take care of them in a timely fashion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schedule</title><link>https://northtexasaikido.com/classes/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://northtexasaikido.com/classes/schedule/</guid><description>&lt;h1>
Class Schedule
 &lt;span class="subheader text-small">March 31, 2025&lt;/span>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The NTA dojo is open for Aikido classes Tuesday, Friday, and Saturday of every week. The dojo is closed on major holidays.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Visitors are always welcome to observe an Aikido class.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>