<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on North Texas Aikido</title><link>https://northtexasaikido.com/</link><description>Recent content in Home on North Texas Aikido</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://northtexasaikido.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Iwama-Style Aikido</title><link>https://northtexasaikido.com/about/aikido/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://northtexasaikido.com/about/aikido/</guid><description>Aikido is written in Japanese using three characters. They are translated as “Ai” - Harmony, “Ki” - Spirit, and “Do” - the Way; or in one translation, &amp;ldquo;The way of spiritual harmony.&amp;rdquo; It is a comparatively modern and extremely sophisticated martial art. Being purely self-defensive, it stresses the avoidance of conflict as an integral part of its philosophical and technical tenets.</description></item><item><title>Contact the Dojo</title><link>https://northtexasaikido.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://northtexasaikido.com/contact/</guid><description>Contact Us You may contact the dojo directly by phone during daylight hours by phone:
972.390.9600 or you may fill out the form below to send a message or question to the dojo.
We will contact you within two business days by phone or email.</description></item><item><title>Dojo Etiquette</title><link>https://northtexasaikido.com/classes/etiquette/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://northtexasaikido.com/classes/etiquette/</guid><description>Etiquette Courtesy in the dojo is more than just a tradition, it is an integral part of Aikido training. By creating a harmonious atmosphere, it aids in learning; and by practicing kindness towards others you work toward self-improvement. A dojo is a special place where people come together for mutual benefit. Here are a few simple things that are considered common courtesy in almost any dojo.
Bow to the Shomen whenever you enter or leave the dojo or step on or off the mat.</description></item><item><title>Dues</title><link>https://northtexasaikido.com/classes/dues/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://northtexasaikido.com/classes/dues/</guid><description>Monthly Dues January 20, 2022 The traditional view is that one cannot buy this type of instruction; it must be given freely and the burden of learning rests solely on the student. The dues and fees you pay are merely a way of insuring that the dojo will be sustained and the at the training and instruction can continue to progress.
Our payment policy is simple. Dues should be paid before the first of the month.</description></item><item><title>Schedule</title><link>https://northtexasaikido.com/classes/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://northtexasaikido.com/classes/schedule/</guid><description> Class Schedule January 20, 2022 The NTA dojo is open for Aikido classes Tuesday through Saturday of every week. Supervised open workout is available on Sundays. The dojo is closed on major holidays.
Visitors are always welcome to observe an Aikido class.
Our class schedule is slowly returning to normal after the pandemic year. Classes are currently open to adult students who have been fully vaccinated against COVID.</description></item></channel></rss>